# Ming Zhang

# Full Stack Developer

Full-stack web developer with over 5 years of experience analyzing, designing, developing, and integrating front-end & back-end based applications. Possesses knowledge of web applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ReactJS, VeuJS, AngularJS, Ajax, and PHP.

Key Achievement: Created a web application that enabled 75,000 users to search for nearby restaurants based on their location with 89% accuracy.

## Contact

#### **Phone**

+852-2868-1340

#### **Email**

prattkate33@gmail.com

#### **Address**

Yau Tsim Mong, Hong Kong

# **Education**

2014 - 2018

**Bachelor of Computer Science** The University of Hong Kong

# Skill

## **Programming Language**

HTML • CSS • JavaScirpt •
TypeScript • Python • Java • C
• C++ • C# • PHP • Ruby •
Go • Rust • SQL

#### **Framework**

ReactJS • AngularJS • VueJS •
NextJS • NuxtJS • Express•
Flask • Django • Spring •
ASP.NET • Laravel • Ruby on

ASP.NET • Laravel •Ruby on Rails

# Database Management System

MySQL • PostgreSQL • MongoDB • Amazon RDS

# **Experience**

## November 2020 - April 2023 Starkford

## **Full Stack Developer**

- Created a web application that enabled 75,000 users to search for nearby restaurants based on their location with 89% accuracy.
- worked with a team of 27 developers that created an e-commerce website in 3 months using PHP, WordPress, MySQL, and JavaScript.
- Developed a responsive email template in HTML5 and CSS3 that increased click-through rates by 78%, an improvement over previous years.
- Participated in code reviews of 300 developers' ensuring that all code was 100% compliant with coding standards & best practices

# February 2019 - October 2020 IrisCX

### **Front End Developer**

- Developed front-end code using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and jQuery to create a responsive web application that works on many devices, including desktops, tablets, and smartphones.
- Optimized 29 web pages for speed and performance by removing unnecessary scripts and styles and increasing load time by 50%.
- Created an interactive map for a real estate company's website that allowed 7K users to search by neighborhood and get real-time feedback on a property.
- Collaborated with 28 UX designers on redesigning other company's existing website; improved conversion rate by 77%

### March 2018 - January 2019

**Bhiner Technologies Limited** 

### **Software Engineer**

- Designed and implemented an automated testing framework using the Python module for unit testing, reducing manual QA time from 3 days to 10 hours per release.
- Reduced development costs by creating reusable components such as database wrappers and authentication modules, which saved Bhiner Technologies \$100,000 annually.
- Initiated a new feature in Bhiner Technologies' flagship product that allows users to search for news.
- Created a web application that allows 2.7K users to create and manage their online accounts for the products.